# Lekhraj Dinkar

• +1 (469) 493 5272 • Lekhrajdinkarus@gmail.com • Irvine(CA) USA

# **Summary**

Over **10** years of experience in financial services with a focus on customized IT solutions. Expertise in microservice architecture and full stack web development utilizing AWS cloud technologies. Demonstrated technical and analytical skills with a track record of transforming complex challenges into effective business solutions.

#### Skills

- Cloud solution with AWS using services -IAM, KMS, S3, SQS, SNS, Event Bridge, Lambda, VPC, ALB, API gateway, Aurora, ECS, EKS, ECR, R53, ACM etc.
- Programming language: Java 17, Typescript/JavaScript
- Scripting language : Python
- Secured REST API with OAuth2.0, JWT and SSL certificate.
- Microservices Architecture.
- Excellent working knowledge of Spring Framework - Spring-Core, Spring-AOP, Spring MVC, Spring REST, Spring Security, Spring boot, Spring JPA Data with Hibernate ORM, Maven
- Frontend technologies: Angular 17
  /Typescript, SCSS, HTML, RxJS reactive programming, NgRX angular
  redux, Angular material, NgPrime
- Experienced in RDBMS design and adequate knowledge in SQL and worked on PostgreSQL(AWS Aurora global)

- ETL pySpark transformation and action.
- Hands On Experience on DevOps.
  - Docker and Kubernetes (AWS EKS)
  - CD/CI pipeline Harness
  - AWS code pipeline
  - Terraform (AWS provider)
  - AWS CDK, AWS cloud formation.
- Experience with Confluent Kafka, RabbitMQ, IBM/MQ
- WebLogic12c and Tomcat server
- Have experience in full development life cycle (SDLC) involving analysis, design, development, testing, implementation and maintenance with agile methodologies.
- Involved in reviewing legacy application architecture and provided Road map for Tech uplift, Migration and Modernization.
- Production Support and release management.

# Experience

Feb 2022 - current

#### Technology Lead - US

Capital Group Companies (contractor: Infosys Limited) | Irvine, USA

MAPS - Multi Asset Portfolio System

**Project Scope**: Building scalable system to support internal and external trading across Mutual Funds and Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs), consisting of three major modules: Inbound, Engine, and Outbound. Led architecture and end-to-end development of the Outbound module.

## Key Technologies & Responsibilities:

- Cloud & Infrastructure: Designed and deployed services using AWS ECS/EKS(Fargate), Lambda, ALB, API Gateway, S3, SQS, SNS, EventBridge, Route 53, ACM, CloudWatch Alarms, VPC endpoints, IAM, KMS, Secret manager.
- Infrastructure as Code & CI/CD: Automated infrastructure with AWS CDK and then with Terraform; implemented CD pipelines using Harness, Docker, and Bash scripting. Performed POC on EKS, Kubernetes, Helm for upcoming EKS migration (HELIX mothership).

#### Application Stack:

Backend: Java 19 (Spring Boot) and Python 3 (FastAPI) with RESTful architecture Python ETL project: with FastApi, SQL Alchemy and PySpark

Frontend: Angular with Redux

Middleware: Integrated RabbitMQ and Confluent Kafka

- Security: Implemented OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect authentication using Okta
- Monitoring: AWS Cloud watch, Datadog Monitor, xMatters

Nov 2018 - Jan 2022

#### Technology Analyst - US, Technology Lead - US

Capital Group Companies (contractor: Infosys Limited) | Irvine, USA

FSR - Fund Sales and Redemption + TACT (target Date fund Allocation)

- Backend technical upgrade Java 8 to Java 11, Hibernate, Struts 2 to Spring Boot web.
- Frontend technical upgrade Adobe Flash to Angular 10.
- Secure API from LDAP to OAuth2, and add SSL certification.
- Mitigate security vulnerabilities in applications
- Perform coding, unit testing, and Code review.
- Proactively involve in design review meetings.
- Creation of client training material and conduct knowledge transfer.
- Onshore-offshore communication and status reporting.
- Work with QA and UAT team to finalize the release scope and timeline.
- Perform production Release planning schedule and management of deliverables.
- Support production issues, replicate issues on development environment and debug the issues.
- Monitored system performance metrics to ensure optimal operation.
- Conducted data backups and disaster recovery operations.

#### Achievements:

- Improved application performance significantly to save business fund processing time from 3 hours to 30 minutes.
- Developed internal framework to manage smooth flow of Swift messaging processing.
- Create tool to simulate Swift inbound message for testing team to enhance and speed up integration testing.
- Improved Application user interfaces by adding expand/collapse, automatic scrolling, improved tabular data visuals, better navigation, color coding scheme with angular.
- Lead offshore development team

Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

#### Senior System Engineer - US

Capital Group Companies (contractor: Infosys Limited) | Irvine, USA

OPAC - Order Processing and check complaince

- Releasing the product to UAT for user testing and setup environment.
- Coding and development, Unit testing and Code review.
- Understanding and analyzing the requirement that comes from the client (CGC) as a part of story document.
- Attend Agile Scrum, Sprint panning, daily standup and retrospective meetings at client location.
- Active interactions with clients and BSA to gather the business requirements.
- Analyzing and recommending the changes required in the current systems and upgrading the current system to latest technologies.
- Evaluating and identifying various technologies available to meet the requirement.
- Support production issues, replicate issues on development environment and debug the issues.
- Perform root-cause analysis of any issues that arise post-implementation and work on solutions related to issue fixing.

#### Feb 2014 - Feb 2017

#### Senior System Engineer, System Engineer

Capital Group Companies (Infosys Limited) | Pune, India

COPS - CRMC order processing System

- Understanding and analyzing the requirement that comes from the client (CGC) as a part of story document.
- Attend Agile Scrum, Sprint panning, daily standup and retrospective meetings.
- Attend design review meetings.
- Project Development and coding.
- Code merge, build and deployment.
- Participate in code and design reviews.
- Handling production issues and debug/replicate the issue on development environment to find the root cause and provide resolution.
- Achievement: Improved batch performance from 45 minutes to 7 minutes to complete the nightly batch completion time.
- POC on JMS communication and integrate it with application to receive data from upstream system asynchronously.

## April 2013 - jan 2014

#### **System Engineer**

SBI - Finacle Migration (Infosys Limited) | Pune, India

- Worked on Finacle Migration project from 7x to 11x version for SBI State Bank of India for 25 countries.
- Develop menu with HTML and JavaScript validation
- Finacle backend script with shell script.

#### Aug 2012 - March 2013

#### **Trainee**

Infosys Limited | Mysore, India

Completed training on

- Software development life cycle
- Java 7
- web development with JSP, html, css, JavaScript
- RDBMs and PL/SQL
- Finacle (Infosys Banking product).

## Education

Bachelor of Technology|Computer Science and Engineering Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology, GGSIPU New Delhi, India|May 2012

#### Websites

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lekhraj-dinkar-25872140/https://github.com/lekhrajdinkar